Alright, great. So we've deployed to rink be using hard hat. This is fantastic.
很好，我们已经用 Hardhat 把合约部署到了 Rinkeby 上，真是太棒了
Now something that we notice, once again is oof,
现在我们会注意到，又一次，哦
our contract isn't verified?
我们的合约没有被验证
Do we have to go back through and do this verify and publish and all that stuff again?
我们需要回去重新验证，发布以及执行其他相关操作么？
Luckily for us, we actually don't need to do that.
幸运的是，我们不需要做这些
So what can we do?
那我们要做的是什么？
Well, back in our deploy script, we can add some code to automatically verify right after we deploy.
回到部署脚本，我们可以添加一些代码以使合约在部署后可以立即自动验证
So let's go ahead and do that.
让我们来试着做一下
Right below our main function, we're gonna create a new function called verify,
在我们的 main 函数下面，我们将创建一个新函数，名为 "verify"
we're gonna say async function, verify.
我们要输入 "async function verify"
And we're gonna have this function get past some arguments,
并且我们要让这个函数接收一些参数
we're gonna have to get past a contract, address, and some arguments or the contract.
我们要提供 "contractAddress" 以及合约所需要的一些参数
Since our simple storage doesn't have a constructor,
因为我们的 "SimpleStorage" 没有构造函数
the arguments for simple storage are just gonna be blank.
所以提供给 "SimpleStorage" 的参数为空
But in the future, when we have contracts that do have constructors,
但是在将来，当我们拥有具有构造函数的合约时
the arguments are going to be populated.
这个参数就不再是空的了
And when we get there, you'll see what I mean,
到那时你就明白我的意思了
we need at least the contract address, and we're going to add some code in here
我们至少要提供 "contractAddress"，并且还要在这里添加一些代码，
to automatically verify our contracts after they've been deployed.
才可以在部署完成后自动验证我们的合约
This auto verification process works on block explorers like ether scan,
这个自动验证过程适用于像 etherscan 这样的区块链浏览器
it might not work on block explorers like eath, pler, or other block explorers.
但可能无法在 "ethplorer" 或其它区块链浏览器上工作
But if you want to verify on these other block explorers,
如果你想要在其它区块链浏览器上进行验证
I'm sure they have an API to allow you to do that as well.
我相信它们也会有自己相应的 API 供你使用
Now, ether scan in most other block explorers have a section on their website
现如今 etherscan 和其它大多数区块链浏览器在它们的网站上都有一个
called API documentation, or something to do with API's.
名为 API 文档("API Documentation") 或是其它与 API 有关的部分
These are ways for us to programmatically interact with ether scan, and do stuff with them.
它们是我们通过编程与 etherscan 进行交互和操作的方式
One of the main things that we can do
其中一件我们要做的主要的事情就是
is we can actually verify our contracts through this API.
通过这些 API 验证我们的合约
Ether scan even has a tutorial in here
etherscan 甚至还提供了一个教程
called verifying contracts programmatically.
就叫做“程序化验证合约”("Verifying Contracts Programmatically")
And the link to this will be in the GitHub repo,
这个网页的链接会放到 GitHub 仓库里
they have an API endpoint that we can make some requests to
他们有一个 API 端点可以让我们向其发送请求
to go ahead and verify our contracts.
以验证我们的合约
Now, we could absolutely make the raw API calls and follow the tutorial here.
现在我们完全可以按着教程进行原始的 API 调用
But there's actually an easier way than even going through this tutorial here.
但实际上有一种甚至是比这个教程更简单的方式
Hardhead is an extensible framework,
Hardhat 是一个可扩展框架
meaning you can add something called plugins to it.
这意味着你可以向其中添加一些被称为插件的东西
There's even an advanced section in the documentation called Building plugins.
文档中会有一个被称为“构建插件”("Building plugins")的高级部分
If we scroll down to the bottom,
如果我们往下拉到底部
we can see some popular plugins that the nomic labs team or the Hardhead team has created.
可以看到一些颇受欢迎的插件，它们是 nomiclabs 或 Hardhat 团队创建的
And also a number of community plugins as well.
同时还有一些社区插件
One of the most used Hardhead plugins is going to be this hard hat ether scan plugin
其中一个使用最广泛的 Hardhat 插件是这个 "hardhat-etherscan"
that makes this verification process much, much easier.
它能使验证过程变得非常非常简单
Install it, you can just run
要想安装它，你只需要运行
npm install bash, just save dev at nomic labs harden ether scan,
"npm install --save-dev @nomiclabs/hardhat-etherscan"
and then add it to our hard hat dot config.
然后把它添加到我们的 "hardhat.config.js" 里就行了
Since we're using yarn, we're just going to go ahead and use yarn.
由于我们使用的是 yarn 所以我们将使用 yarn 来完成这件事
So back in our code, we'll do yarn, add dash dash Dev, at nomic, labs, slash hard hat slash hyphen, ether scan.
回到我们的代码，运行 "yarn add --dev @nomiclabs/hardhat-etherscan"
Now that we have this plugin,
现在我们有了这个插件
we can go to our hard hat dot config, scroll to the top and add this plugin
就可以到 "hardhat.config" 里，拉到顶部添加这个插件了
do require at nomic labs slash hard hat, ether scan.
输入 "require(@nomiclabs/hardhat-etherscan)"
Now that we have this plugin,
现在我们就拥有这个插件了
the hard hat documentation has some more information about the usage,
Hardhat 文档中有更多“使用”("Usage")信息
how to actually use this plugin, and how to run different commands with it.
包括如何使用这些插件以及如何运行各种不同的命令
In order for us to use this verification,
为了能使用这个东西进行验证
we actually need an API key from ether scan.
我们还需要从 etherscan 获取一个 "API key"
This is basically a password for allowing us to use the ether scan API.
基本上它就是一个允许我们使用 etherscan API 的密码
So we're going to come to ether scan.
所以我们要来到 etherscan
And we're going to go ahead and sign in.
接着继续选择“登录”(Sign In)
And actually we're going to click to sign up and create an account.
实际上，我们要做的是“点击以注册”("Click to sign up")并创建一个账号
And we'll go ahead and create an account.
接着点击“创建一个账号”("Create an Account")
We'll go ahead and verify our registration by clicking the verification link. And we'll click the Login.
接着点击验证链接以验证我们的注册，然后点击“登录”("Click to Login")
Now that we're logged in. On the left hand side, we can scroll down to API keys.
现在我们就已经登录好了，把左侧往下拉，拉到 "API Keys"
And we can go ahead and create a new API key.
我们就可以来创建一个新的 "API key" 了，
We call this H H hyphen sec, which stands for hardhat Free Code Camp.
我们把它叫做 "HH-FCC" 表示 "Hardhat Free Code Camp"
Great, this new API key will copy this and we'll go back to our code and we'll add this somewhere
复制这个新创建的 "API key"，并回到我们的代码中添加到某个地方
since the API keys basically considered a password.
由于这个 "API key" 基本上就可以认为是一个密码
Where do you think we should add this? That's right in our dot env.
所以你认为我们应该添加到哪里去呢？没错，就是我们的 ".env"
So in our dot env, we're going to add a new entry called ether scan API key.
来到我们的 ".env" 添加一个新的条目名为 "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY"
And we're going to add that API key that we just got.
并把我们刚刚获得 "API key" 添加到这里
Now that we have our API key,
现在我们就拥有了 "API key"
back in our Hardhead, config, we're going to create a new section in a module dot exports,
回到我们的 "hardhat.config"，我们将在 "module.exports" 中创建一个新的部分
tell hardhat that we have this ether scan API key,
以告诉 Hardhat 我们拥有的这个 etherscan "API key"
or new section is going to be called ether scan.
这个新部分的名字是 "etherscan"
And in here, we're gonna say API key is going to be ether scan API key
这里我们要写 "apikey"，它是 "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY"
that we're going to define up here the same way we define these other keys.
现在我们要在这里定义它就像定义其它密钥一样
So we'll say const, ether scan API key equals process dot e NV dot ether scan API key.
我们输入 "const ETHERSCAN_API_KEY = process.env.ETHERSCAN_API_KEY"
And if something like this pops up, you can generally just hit enter,
如果弹出了这样的东西，通常你可以直接按回车
and it will autocomplete it for you, which is awesome.
这样它就会自动为你补全，非常爽
Great. So now we have an ether scan API key
很好，现在我们已经有了 etherscan "API key"
back in the heart had documentation, it tells us by adding this,
回到 Hardhat 文档，它告诉我们只要添加这个
we actually get a new task called verify.
就可以执行一种名为 "verify" 的新 task
Let's try that out. So open our terminal back up.
嗯，让我们来试试看吧，打开我们的终端
And we'll do yarn, RT hat. Let's see what pops up.
运行 "yarn hardhat"，看看会出来些什么
Wow, we did get a new verification here.
哇，我们真的可以执行这个 "verify" 了
When we run yarn hard hat harder, it actually looks into our hard hat.config.js and checks for any plugins.
当我们运行 "yarn hardhat" 的时候，它会去检查 "hardhat.config.js" 中的所有插件
If there are new plugins there,
如果里面有新的插件存在
it'll add them as a new task that we can do.
它就会将其作为新的 task 添加进来以便我们能够使用
You can manually verify your contract by doing yarn or MPX Harnett verify dash dash network,
你可以手动验证你的合约，方法是运行 "yarn" 或 "npx hardhat verify --network"
the deployed contract address and any constructor arguments yourself.
后面是已部署合约的地址以及任何你需要的构造函数参数
But we want to be a little bit more programmatic than this.
但我们想让这个过程更加程序化
So what we're going to do
所以我们要做的是
is we're going to go back and create this verification function,
返回去继续创建这个验证函数
it is good to know how to do it via command line
不过知道如何通过命令行执行验证还是很好的
so that if you want to verify something in the future, manually, you can,
这样你将来想手动进行验证的时候就知道怎么做了
let's build this verify function though.
让我们现在开始构建这个 "verify" 函数
So we're going to take the our contract address and some arguments.
它需要获取我们的合约地址以及一些其它参数
And for our sake, we're going to do console dot log verifying contract that that
接着我们输入 "console.log("Verifying contract...")"
just so that we know we might have to wait for a little bit.
这只是为了让我们知道可能需要在这里等候一会儿
And in our code, we can actually run any task from hard hat using a run package.
在我们的代码中，我们可以使用 "run" 包来运行 Hardhat 中的所有 task
So up at the top, we're actually going to import run from hard hat as well
所以在代码顶部，我们需要从 "hardhat" 中一并导入 "run"
run allows us to run any hard hat task.
"run" 允许我们运行所有的 Hardhat task
So in our code here, we're going to do a wait to run. And then we can do there it thought.
所以在我们的代码这里，执行 "await run()"，接着是 "verify"
Now part of that allows you to add different parameters as well in this run.
Hardhat 允许你在 "run" 中添加不同的参数
And it's usually best that you go ahead and add them in here
最好是在此处就添加上
so that we're really specific with what we're doing.
这样我们才能明确我们现在做什么
If we do yarn hardhat verify dash dash help,
如果我们运行 "yarn hardhat verify --help"
we can see what parameters we can actually pass.
就能看到我们可以传递哪些参数
Well, it looks like we can pass the Verify parameter.
看起来我们可以传递 "verify" 参数
So we'll do colon, verify.
所以我们要写上 ":verify"
If you go to the actual GitHub for the verification tasks,
如果你去查看 verify task 的 GitHub 页面
you can actually see you can do more than just verify,
就会发现你不止可以进行 "verify" 操作
you can do verify, get minimum build,
还可以执行 "verify:get-minimum-build"
verify, get constructor arguments,
"verify:get-constructor-arguments"
verify, verify, which is what we're going to be working with,
"verify:verify"，这正是我们要使用的功能
and a couple of other subtasks as well.
以及一些其它的子 task
The second parameter that goes inside run is going to be a list of actual parameters.
第二个传入 "run" 的参数将是一个实际参数的列表
This second parameter here is just kind of the sub task, if you will, of our verify task.
如果你愿意的话，这里的第二个参数可以说成是 "verify" task的一个子 task
And this is going to be an object that contains the actual parameters.
并且它会是一个包含实际参数的对象
And this is where we pass in an address,
这里我们传入一个 "address"
which is going to be our contract address,
即我们的 "contractAddress"
and then our construct or arguments, which is going to be arcs.
接着是我们的 "constructorArguments" 即 "args"
Now normally just this right here should be enough for us to go ahead and use this verify contract in our main function,
通常情况下，这些东西就足够我们在 main 函数中使用这个合约验证了
but we're going to add one additional thing to it.
但我们还要额外添加一个东西
Because in practice, sometimes there's some errors that can come up.
因为在实践中，有时会出现一些错误
One of the errors that often comes up when running a wait
其中一个经常会遇到的错误是，在运行 "await" 的时候
is that the contract has already been verified.
合约已经被验证过了
而且你很可能经常会遇到这个问题
because ether scan will get smart enough
因为 etherscan 足够智能
by seeing enough bytecode that is exactly simple storage
它已经看到过足够多形如 SimpleStorage 的字节码
that it will start to just automatically verify any bytecode that looks like simple storage.
因此它会自动验证任何看起来像是 SimpleStorage 的字节码
And then this await will throw an error, which we want to avoid.
这时 "await" 就会抛出一个错误，这正是我们想要避免的
So what we can do is we can add a try catch onto this await.
我们可以做的是在 await 这里添加一个 "try catch"
So outside of the way, we're going to add a try.
所以在 await 外面，我们要添加一个 try
And we're going to add these little brackets that wrap around our weight.
还要添上这些括号包住我们的 await
And then we're going to put a catch.
接着在这里放一个 "catch(e)"
This is known as a try, catch and solidity also has tried catches.
这就是所谓的 "try catch"，Solidity 也有 "try catch"
But basically, this e is going to be any error that this section throws.
基本上来说，这个 "e" 指的就是这部分抛出的任何错误
So we're going to do is we're going to say if this message is already verified,
所以我们要做的就是，如果这段消息已经被验证过了
then we're just going to continue.
那么就继续运行其余的代码
So we're gonna say if e.message.to lowercase,
所以就是 "if (e.message.toLowerCase())"
we're going to make sure it's to lowercase
这里要确保它变成全小写的
that includes already there. If five,
".includes("already verified")"
then we're just going to console dot log already verified like that.
接着是 "console.log("Already Verified!")"
Otherwise, we're just going to console dot log e.
否则，我们要运行 "console.log(e)"
The reason we do This is because of this errors, our verification function will break,
之所以要这么做是因为这个错误会导致我们的验证过程中断
and our whole script will end.
并且我们的整个脚本都会终止运行
And we don't want our whole script to end,
我们当然不希望整个脚本就此终止
we want our script to keep continuing if the verification doesn't work, because it's not really a big deal.
我们想要的是即便验证过程中断，脚本也要继续运行，因为这并不是什么大问题
So I know this might seem like a lot of code,
我知道这一段代码确实显得有些多
feel free to copy and paste it from the GitHub repo to just move along.
所以你可以从 GitHub 仓库中复制粘贴这一段以继续前进
But awesome. So we now have a verify function using the Verify task in hardhat.
很好，现在我们有了一个可以使用 Hardhat 进行 "verify" task 的 "verify" 函数
Let's go ahead and use this now in our main function,
让我们继续，在 main 函数中实际使用一下它
right below our deploy,
在我们的 "deploy()" 下方
we'll do console dot log deployed contract two, and then the contract address.
我们运行了 "console.log('Deploy contract to: ')" 然后是合约地址
But before we call this main function, let's think for a quick second.
但在我们调用这个 main 函数之前，让我们再次快速思考一下
What happens when we deploy to our RT Hat Network?
在我们部署到 Hardhat 网络时到底发生了什么？
Well, remember, if we deploy to our Hard Hat Network,
如果我们部署到的是 Hardhat 网络
will our contract need to be verified I need to scan?
那么我们的合约还需要 etherscan 的验证么
Well, we know there's a we know there's a rink ether scan,
我们知道，有一个 "Rinkeby etherscan"
we know there's a COVID ether scan, we know there's a main net easy scan.
我们还知道除了这个 etherscan 还有主网络的 etherscan
But is there a Hardhead ether scan? No, of course not. Right?
但是有 "Hardhat etherscan" 么？没有，当然没有了，对吧？
The hard at runtime environment is a network local to our machine.
Hardhat 运行环境是一个位于我们本地机器上的网络
So it doesn't make sense for us to verify a hard hat network deployed contract on ether scan.
因此对部署到 Hardhat 网络的合约进行 etherscan 验证是毫无意义的
So we actually don't want to call this verify function,
所以我们并不打算实际调用这个 "verify" 函数
when we're working with our local network.
在我们使用本地网络进行工作时
This is where these chain IDs are going to come in quite useful.
这就是这些 "chainID" 的有用之处了
What we can do is we can check to see if the network that we're running on
我们可以检查一下我们运行的网络
is a live network or it's a test net, or it's a network that actually can be verified,
究竟是一个实时网络还是一个测试网络，或者说是一个可以验证的网络
we can actually get network configuration information by importing a network like this.
我们可以通过导入一个 "network" 包来获取网络配置信息，就像这样
And we can do something like console dot log network dot config.
然后我们就可以执行 "console.log(network.config)"
Now, if I run yarn, art, hit run scripts deploy.js.
现在，如果我运行 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.js"
On our Hard Hat Network,
在我们的 Hardhat network 上
since I'm not passing a network flag,
由于我没有传入任何网络标识
we get this massive output that looks like this.
我们得到了这么一大堆输出，看起来就像这样
Our network dot config contains a ton of information about the current network that we're on,
"network.config" 中包含了有关我们当前所在网络的大量信息
you'll see here that the chain ID of the Hardhead network is actually 31337
这里可以看到 "Hardhat network" 的 "chainID" 是 31337
gas price, which gets set to auto
gasPrice 被设置为了 "auto"
block gas limit the current fork of Aetherium that we're working with,
"blockGasLimit" 还有当前我们所使用的以太坊分支
and all these other pieces here.
以及其它所有有关的信息
This chain ID is really important.
这个 "chainID" 真的非常重要
Because we can use this chain ID to figure out
因为我们可以用这个 "chainID" 来确定
which one is a test net, or which one is a live network.
哪一个是测试网络，哪一个是实时网络
And remember, running the script is going to be the same as doing dash dash network, hard hat,
并且记住，运行这个脚本等同于执行 "--network hardhat"
you'll see our channel ID is still 31337.
可以看到我们的 "chainID" 仍然是 31337
Again, that's because the default network in our heart had config, it's hard hat,
这是因为 "hardhat.config" 中的 "defaultNetwork" 仍然是 "hardhat"
which is the same as saying every single time we run a script,
这就是说每次我们运行这个脚本的时候
we're secretly running it with dash dash network hard hat.
都相当于在后台使用了一次 "--network hardhat"
So now we only want to verify on our test net.
现在我们只想在测试网络上进行验证
So what we can do
可以这样做
is we can say if network dot config, that chain ID equals equals equals four,
"if (network.config.chainID === 4)"
which is going to be rank B, ad.
它表示 Rinkeby
And a JavaScript equals equals equals is nearly the same as equals equals,
在 JavaScript 中 "==="  和 "==" 几乎相同
except no type conversion is done,
唯一的区别是它不进行类型转换
which just means in JavaScript, four equals four, and four equals equals the string of four,
这意味着在 JavaScript 中 “4 == 4” 和 “4 == "4"”
but four, but if you were to use four equals equals equals four, this is false.
但如果你用的是 “4 === "4"” 这个输出的是 false
This is true
这个是 true
equals equals four equals equals would be true, four equals equals to the string of four would also be true,
“== 4” 是 true，“4 == "4"” 也是 true
but four equals equals equals to the string of four is going to be false.
但 “4 === "4"” 则是 false
So you can kind of do whatever you want here
你可以在这里采取你想用的方式
equals equals or equals equals equals.
"==" 或是 "===" 都可以
So we want to say if the network dot config dot Trinity is four,
所以我们做的就是，如果 "network.config.chainID" 是 4
so if we're on Rinkeby,
即，如果我们是在 Rinkeby 上
then we can go ahead and actually verify.
那么，我们就进行验证
But we also want to make sure we only verify if our ether scan API key exists.
但我们还要确保只有当我们的 "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY" 存在的情况下才进行验证
So we can also in here is site and this double ampersand means and
所以我们可以在这里添加一个“与”判断，这个 "&&" 的意思就是“(逻辑)与”
we can say process dot e NV dot ether scan API key.
我们要写的是 "process.env.ETHERSCAN_API_KEY"
This is some Boolean tricks that we're doing here, basically,
这里我们使用了一些布尔值运算技巧
so our first conditional we're saying if network dot config chinati equals equals equals four,
我们的第一个条件是判断 "network.config.chainID === 4"
this section can be true or false, obviously, right?
这一段可以是真也可以是假，很明显，对吧？
The chain ID that we're running on can be the hardest network,
我们现在是在 "Hardhat network" 上运行的
which would mean this doesn't equal four,
这意味着 "chainID" 不等于 4
or it would be Rinckey, which means this does equal four.
如果我们是在 Rinkeby 上的话，它就等于 4 了
But there's no conditional on this side. So how does this side work?
但这一边并不是一个条件，那么它是如何工作的呢？
In JavaScript, if an object exists,
在 JavaScript 中，如果一个对象存在
and you try to cast it as a Boolean, it will be converted to true.
并且你要试图把它转换为布尔值，那么它就会被转换为 true
If it doesn't exist, it will be converted to false.
如果它不存在，就会被转换为 false
So in JavaScript, basically, if either scan API key exists,
所以在 JavaScript 中，如果 "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY" 存在
if we have this in our data in VI, this will be true.
即，我们在 ".env" 中有这个值的话，它就是 true
And if not, this will be false.
如果没有，它就是 false
So another way to read this line here is saying
因此这一行的的另一种理解方式就是
if network dot config that Trinity is for AKA, if we're on rink B,
如果 "network.config.chainID" 是 4，也就是说如果我们是在 Rinkeby 上
and our ether scan API key exists, then do some stuff.
并且 "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY" 也存在，则执行以下操作
And that's what we're going to do here.
这就是我们正在做的事情
So in here, we'd want to run verify, or verify function
这里面，我们要运行 "verify()" 或者说 "verify" 函数
and pass it the contract address which is going to be Simple Storage dot address and the constructor arguments
并传入合约地址，就是 "SimpleStorage.address" 以及构造函数参数
which we know are going to be blank.
不过我们知道它是空白的
And since our verify function is an async function, and it deals with promises and stuff,
由于我们的 "verify" 函数是一个异步函数，并且涉及 Promise 等内容
we want to add the await keyword here.
所以我们要在这里添上 await 关键字
Awesome. So we've added a way to actually verify our contract. But we're not quite done.
太好了，我们已经添加了一个验证合约的方法，但到此可并没完呢
See on ether scan and all these block explorers the instant we deploy the contract and the instant we send the contract,
在 etherscan 和所有的区块浏览器上，当我们部署并发送合约的时候
ether scan might not know about the transaction yet,
etherscan 可能还并不知道有这个交易
it might take a hot second for ether scan to be up to speed with where the blockchain is.
etherscan 可能还需要一小段时间才能跟上区块链的变化
So it's usually best practice to wait for a few blocks to be mined, until you actually run your verification process.
所以实践中最好是先等几个区块被挖出来，然后再进行你的验证操作
We've actually learned how to do this already with the deploy transaction.
我们实际上已经在部署交易时学过怎么实现这个操作了
So before we actually verify
所以在我们进行验证之前
we run, we want to run a weight, simple storage. Deploy transaction Wait, six.
我们要运行 "await SimpleStorage.deployTransaction.wait(6)"
So we will wait six blocks,
所以我们将等待六个区块
and then we'll run our verification process.
随后再执行我们的验证过程
Now, if you want to go and test this out right now, you absolutely can.
现在，如果你想要立即测试一下的话，也可以
I'm going to keep going, though,
但我会先接着往下走
because again, testing all these on a test net takes a little bit of extra time.
还是因为，在测试网上测试这些东西，实在是比较费时间
So I'm going to finish the rest of our main function,
所以我要先完成 main 函数的剩余部分
and then I'm going to run everything all together.
然后再一并运行它们